Isaac Holt

 ± 44 7393 098225 | isaac_holt@icloud.com | linkedin.com/in/isaacholt100 | GitHub | Personal Website

Summary

Highly capable mathematician, with a final year average grade of 97% at undergraduate (the highest in my year), who excels at tackling difficult and technical problems. Strong skills in a variety of programming languages and owner of a popular Rust library with over 500,000 downloads. Experience in mathematical research, soon-to-be co-author of a paper on tropical geometry. Focussed and driven, with a passion for setting challenging goals and achieving them.

Education

Durham University, BSc Mathematics

09/2021 - 06/2024

- Classification: First Class Honours.
- Grade: 95% (joint-highest in my cohort).
- Awards: The Mathematical Sciences Best 3H Student Prize

University of Cambridge, MASt in Mathematics

10/2024 - 06/2024

Colchester Royal Grammar School

09/2019 - 06/2021

- A Levels: Mathematics (A*), Further Mathematics (A*), Physics (A*), Latin (A*).
- Awards: Year 13 Prize for Further Mathematics.

Research Experience

Research Project in Tropical Geometry

06/2023 - 07/2023

Department of Mathematical Sciences, Durham University

- Area of research was how the tropical modification of certain polynomial systems can be used to determine the generic root count of those systems.
- The results of our work are expected to be published in a paper by the end of this year.
- Invited by supervisor to attend a <u>working group</u> for the OSCAR computer algebra system in Germany, to write code related to the project.

Work Experience

Web and Communications Internship

07/2023 - 08/2023

Grey College, Durham University

- Created a <u>new website</u> for Grey College Senior Common Room, using React, Next.js, Bootstrap, and KV storage.
- Built an admin dashboard with an email client for sending markdown emails and templated emails.
- Developed a password-less email authentication system.

Student Digital Leader

09/2022 - 06/2023

Durham University

- Part of a pool of students who worked on various technical projects for the university.
- For the first few weeks, I worked in online support with the university's digital services for new students.
- I then worked as a UAT (User Acceptance Testing) Analyst within this role, using Azure DevOps and Jira to pass/fail test cases and report bugs for a new event-booking website that the university is launching.

Software Tester 01/2021 - 03/2021

Blutick

- Tested Blutick's marking software for online GCSE maths exams, reported bugs I found when using the website.
- Given the responsibility of editing the online questions and mark schemes myself using Latex.
- Developed TypeScript program to generate all solutions for questions where many combinations of answers were allowed.

Projects

bnum 05/2021 - Present

Mathematical <u>Rust library</u> with over 500,000 downloads that uniquely provides fixed size signed and unsigned integer types, designed to extend functionality of Rust's primitive integer types to arbitrary bit sizes. Used by a blockchain-related package.

Extracurriculars

Piano (ABRSM Grade 8 Distinction) | Durham University Chess Society | Durham University Spaceflight Society | Durham University Mathematical Problem Solving Society | Grey College Table Tennis A Team | Grey College Badminton B Team | Durham University Chess Society | Durham University Quant Fund | Co-leader of Physics and Maths Society at Sixth Form

Skills

Mathematics | Rust | JavaScript | Python | Latex | Programming | Research

Isaac Holt

+447393098225 | isaac holt@icloud.com | linkedin.com/in/isaacholt100

Summary

Highly capable third year undergraduate mathematician with current average mark of 91%. Seeking admission into the MASt in Mathematics, with wide-ranging interests in areas such as number theory, combinatorics and quantum computation. Driven and committed to expanding and deepening my mathematical knowledge and discovering new results, as the co-author of a paper on tropical geometry which has been submitted as a chapter for a forthcoming book.

Education

Durham University, MMath Mathematics

09/2021 - Present

- Third year modules: Analysis, Cryptography and Codes, Galois Theory, Number Theory, Quantum Computing, Topology.
- Grade: 1st (expected). First year average: 90%, second year average: 92%.
- Notable marks (1st year): Discrete Mathematics: 90% | Analysis: 91% | Linear Algebra: 96%.
- Notable marks (2nd year): Algebra: 94% | Complex Analysis: 95% | Elementary Number Theory: 98%.

Colchester Royal Grammar School

09/2019 - 06/2021

- A-levels: Mathematics (A*, 99%), Further Mathematics (A*, 97%), Physics (A*, 91%), Latin (A*, 90%).
- Awards: Year 13 Prize for Further Mathematics I was selected for this prize out of the 50 or so students in my cohort taking Further Mathematics A-level.

Research Experience

Summer Research Project - Department of Mathematical Sciences, Durham University 06/2023 - 07/2023

- Area of research was in tropical geometry; specifically, how the modification and tropicalisation of horizontally parametrised polynomial systems can be used to determine the generic root count of those systems.
- First four weeks were mostly spent learning about the area and reading relevant books and materials.
- Last four weeks were devoted to formulating and proving a new result, where I produced a generalised proof of a theorem from a recent paper on the number of equilibria of coupled nonlinear oscillators.
- Paper has been published on <u>arXiv</u> and submitted as a chapter for the upcoming book on the OSCAR computer algebra system.
- Invited by my supervisor to attend a <u>working group</u> for OSCAR at Paderborn University, Germany, to write an illustrative <u>program</u> in Julia for the paper.

(Upcoming) Mitacs Globalink Research Internship - University of British Columbia 06/2024 - 08/2024

Work Experience

Web and Communications Internship - Grey College, Durham University

07/2023 - 08/2023

• Developed the <u>new website</u> for my college's Senior Common Room, using my programming abilities.

Student Digital Leader - Durham University

09/2022 - 06/2023

• Worked as a User Acceptance Testing Analyst, using Azure DevOps to pass/fail test cases and report bugs for a new event-booking website that the university is launching.

Software Tester - Blutick

01/2021 - 03/2021

- Used my capacity for mathematical rigour to test the marking software for online GCSE maths exams.
- Having excelled in this task, was given the responsibility of editing the questions using Latex.
- Developed computer program to generate all solutions for questions where many combinations of answers were allowed.

Publications

Holt, I., & Ren, Y. (2023). Generic root counts of tropically transverse systems – An invitation to tropical geometry in OSCAR. Available at arXiv:2311.18018.

Projects

bnum 05/2021 - Present

- Mathematical <u>Rust library</u> for operating on arbitrarily-sized integers, with over 250,000 downloads.
- Is a dependency for two other libraries, including a popular smart contract <u>package</u>.
- To my knowledge, it is the only library to extend functionality of Rust's primitive integer types to arbitrary, fixed size signed and unsigned integers.
- Development involved researching arithmetical algorithms, e.g. Knuth's integer division algorithm and exponentiation by squaring.

Relevant skills

- Mathematical research experience, including helping produce a paper in 2023 on tropical geometry.
- Experience reading mathematical publications (currently reading *Mathematical Logic* by Cori and Lascar).
- Experience in the typsetting languages Latex and Typst typeset notes for my undergraduate modules are available on my <u>website</u>.
- Programming experience in a variety of languages: Rust, Python, Julia, R, JavaScript, TypeScript.

Extracurriculars

- Co-leader of Physics and Maths Society at Sixth Form
- Durham University Mathematical Problem Solving Society
- Simon Marais Mathematics Competition (2022, 2023)
- Imperial-Cambridge Mathematics Competition (2022, 2023)
- British Mathematical Olympiad (2020)
- Classical Piano (ABRSM Grade 8 Distinction, working towards the ARSM diploma)
- Durham University Chess Society
- Durham University Spaceflight Society
- Grey College Badminton B Team
- Grey College Table Tennis A Team
- Durham University Table Tennis Development Squad